A Guide to the Stafford (Va.) Records, 1664-1931
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Stafford County (Va.) Records, 1664-1931
The Library of Virginia
1051099, 1051101-1051102, 1146905, 1156704, 1168268, 1181872-1181883, 1199312-1199315, 1199321
13 v. (photostats), 4.5 cu. ft. (10 boxes)
Stafford County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in a shipment of court records from Stafford County. Portions of the collection were transferred under the following accession numbers: 14048, 20588, 20815, 21190-21192, 21290, 22426, 22515, 22792, 23514, 23854 and 44155.
Historical Information
Stafford County was formed from Westmoreland county in 1664. Part of King George County was added on 1 January 1777. The county was named for the English County.
Many pre-Civil War court records were lost to vandalism by Union troops during the Civil War. A few volumes that record deeds, court orders, and wills exist.
The records found in this collection were also created by the County Court, the Superior Courts of Chancery and Law and the Circuit Superior Court of Law and Chancery.
Scope and Content
Stafford County (Va.) Records, 1664-1924, include various records from the following series: Bonds/Commissions/Oaths, County Administrative Records, Court Records, Election Records, Fiduciary Records, Health and Medical Records, Justice of the Peace Records, Land Records, Marriage Records, Military and Pension Records, Miscellaneous Records, Organization Records, Tax and Fiscal Records, Town Administrative Records and Wills.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Stafford County Records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm" found on the Library of Virginia's web site.
Related Material
Stafford County is one of Virginia's Lost Records Localities. Additional Stafford County Court Records may be found in the Virginia Lost Records Localities Collection at the Library of Virgina. Search the Lost Records Localities Database found on the Library of Virginia's web site.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Stafford County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Public records--Virginia--Stafford County.
Geographical Names:
Stafford County (Va.)--History.
Genre and Form Terms:
Local government records--Virginia--Stafford County.
Added Entry - Corporate Name:
Stafford County (Va.) Circuit Superior Court of Law and Chancery.; Stafford County (Va.) County Court.; Stafford County (Va.) Superior Court of Chancery.
Contents List
- Records, 1671-1797
  writs, summons, accounts, plats, bonds
- Records, 1664-1868
  Town of Falmouth Trustee Proceedings, Court Records, Miscellaneous Records
- Records, 1701-1797
  Will of William Fitzhugh [19th Century copy], 1701; Fragment of page from Order Book, 1712; Writ, Campbell vs. Burton, 1745; Fieri Facias, Nicholson vs. Joby, 1746; Will of Taylor Chapman, 1749/1750; Summons, Gutterie vs. Fitzhugh, 1760; Account, Estate of George Hedgman, 1763; Bond of Elias Hore, Administrator of Isabella Harrison, dec'd, 1763; Summons, Burgess Administrator vs. Ramy, 1764; Plat of prison bounds of Stafford County by Travers Daniel, 1765; Writ, Wilkinson vs. Hay, 1767; Summons, How vs. Scandland, 1768; Writ, Hay vs. Green, 1767; Summons, Burwell vs. Brown, 1769; Bond, Travers Daniel as Guardian to John Hedgman, 1772; Capias, Hoar vs. Stone, 1773; Bill (Account), Andrew Farce to Mary Price, 1778; Summons, Price vs. Farce, 1778; Will of Elizabeth Withers, 1797; Various photocopies from microfilm.
- General Index to Deed Books Libers K-NN, 1721-1845 (photostat)
  includes wills, appraisements, inventories, estate accounts, estate divisions, deeds, bonds (A-Z by page number)
- Records, 1723-1806
  Rent Rolls, 1723, 1768, 1773; Memorandum concerning James Carter's Rent Roll, 1729; Lectures on Grammar, 1806: Writ - Ann Lewis to appear in court, 1784; Bonds, Writs, Petitions, Orders, 1747-1785
- Records, 1671-1672
  14 December 1671-15 February 1672 includes depositions, deeds and wills
- Index of Records of Stafford County, 1664-1914, Vol. 1, Ab-Ca, Grantee (photostat)
  Index of Deeds, Deeds of Trust, Release Deeds and Wills
- Index of Records of Stafford County, 1664-1914, Vol. 2, Ce-Fi, Grantee (photostat)
- Index of Records of Stafford County, 1664-1914, Vol. 3, Fi-Hy, Grantee (photostat)
- Index of Records of Stafford County, 1664-1914, Vol. 4, In-Mo, Grantee (photostat)
- Index of Records of Stafford County, 1664-1914, Vol. 5, Mu-Sk, Grantee (photostat)
- Index of Records of Stafford County, 1664-1914, Vol. 6, Sla-Z, Grantee (photostat)
- Index of Records of Stafford County, 1664-1914, Vol.1, Cb-Ch, Grantor (photostat)
- Index of Records of Stafford County, 1664-1914, Vol.2 Cl-Fu, Grantor (photostat)
- Index of Records of Stafford County, 1664-1914, Vol.3, Ga-Ju, Grantor (photostat)
- Index of Records of Stafford County, 1664-1914, Vol.4, Ka-My, Grantor (photostat)
- Index of Records of Stafford County, 1664-1914, Vol.5, Na-Sn, Grantor (photostat)
- Index of Records of Stafford County, 1664-1914, Vol.6, So-Yo, Grantor (photostat)
- Records, 1903; 1905-1914; 1917; 1919 (Unprocessed)
  Judgments
- Records, 1857-1931; undated (Unprocessed)
- Records, 1820-1927; undated (Unprocessed)
  County Administrative Records, Court Records, Election Records, Fiduciary Records, Justice of the Peace Records, Land Records and Tax and Fiscal Records
- Records, 1873-1901; 1906-1923 (Unprocessed)
  Bonds/Commissions/Oaths, Court Records, County Administrative Records, Election Records,Fiduciary Records, Health and Medical Records, Land Records, Military and Pension Records, Miscellaneous Records, Organization Records and Tax and Fiscal Records
- Records, 1902-1906 (Unprocessed)
  Judgments related to Martin's Admr v. Richmond, Fredericksburt and Potomac Railroad